Rickie H. Dixon Jr.

727-642-7851 | University Place, WA | rhdixon79@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github | rickiedixon.com

SUMMARY

Adaptive full stack web developer with front and back end knowledge. Hard working and collaborative individual who is ready to bring an enthusiastic attitude to the Adobe work environment with a background in customer service and architectural design. These combined experiences help to bring a critical eye to new projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React
- Java
- Python
- JavaScript

- HTML
- CSS
- MySQL
- MongoDB

- Django
- Spring
- Express.JS
- BootStrap

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Crwn Clothing | React

- Website built using React that leverages Firebase cloud firestore for backend support.
- Google sign in integration for authorization and to ease facilitation of user information.
- Implemented styled components to streamline styling.

Handy Helper | Python

- Application created using Django framework
- Utilizing CRUD commands jobs can be created, given away or deleted
- Users may also add jobs from other users to their own list of jobs and mark them as done once completed
- User access provided by Django-authentication to ensure protection of account

Study Buddy | React

- A study timer created using React/Bootstrap based on the Pomodoro study technique
- Timer is equipped with standard functionality (i.e. start, stop and time increment/decrement/ reset)
- Users access their Spotify account (with Spotify API authenticate) to enjoy focus music while studying or working on a project

EDUCATION

Coding Dojo | Full-Stack Developer Certificate | Bellevue, WA

• Immersive Full-Stack training program in Python, Java and MERN

2021

Saint Petersburg College | A.A. in Architectural Design | Saint Petersburg, FL

• Studied conceptual and practical application of architectural design

2008

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bartender | The Matador | Tacoma, WA

2021-Present

- Increased bar sales 15% by upselling key menu items.
- Utilize multitasking skills by providing bar service and customer care in an efficient manner
- Provide training for multiple staff members ensuring adherence to established guidelines

Bartender | Garage Bowl & Billiards | Seattle, WA

2016-2020

- Handled high volume bar with attention to detail
- Catered event hosting
- Keeping customer experience a top priority

Carpenter | MESH, LLC. Architecture/Fabrication | Saint Petersburg, FL

2009-2016

- Read blueprints to compile cut list and check for adequate material inventory
- Assembled and installed custom cabinetry and furniture
- Responsibly delivered finished materials on schedule